but foremost, we had to come up with a design process to reuse these randomly shaped rocks, and we had not done this before. Today everything would be much easier because we would go to the quarry with our smartphones equipped with 3-D scanners and we would document each rock, turn that into a digital model -- highly engineer the whole process. But more than a decade ago, we had to embrace uncertainty and put on our boots, roll up our sleeves and move to the quarry for a hands-on experience. And we also had to become the contractors because we failed at finding somebody willing to share the risk with us. Now, luckily, we convinced the quarry team to help us build a few prototypes to resolve some of the technical details. And we agreed on a few mock-ups, but we got excited, and one stone led to another until we succeeded to build an 18-meter-long by eight-meter-high structure that recycled all the amorphous material of the quarry,
aunque, principalmente, debíamos pensar en un proceso de diseño para reutilizar estas piedras talladas al azar. Algo que no habíamos hecho antes. Hoy en día, todo sería más fácil porque iríamos a la cantera con nuestros teléfonos inteligentes equipados con escáneres 3D, documentaríamos cada piedra y lo convertiríamos en un modelo digital. Todo el proceso muy mecanizado. Pero hace más de diez años, teníamos que abrazar la incertidumbre, ponernos manos a la obra e ir a la cantera por la experiencia práctica. También tuvimos que ser los contratistas porque no encontramos a nadie que quisiera correr el riesgo con nosotros. Por suerte, el equipo de la cantera nos ayudó a construir algunos prototipos que resolverían algunos de los detalles técnicos. Estuvimos de acuerdo con algunos modelos, nos entusiasmamos, y una piedra llevó a la otra hasta que logramos construir una estructura de 18 metros de largo por 8 metros de alto que recicló todo el material amorfo de la cantera
just supported by gravity -- no mortar and no ties. And once built and tested, moving it to the final site in the city center to unite it with the rest of the building was a piece of cake, because by having isolated uncertainty and managed risk in the controlled environment of the quarry, we were able to complete the whole building in time and on budget, even if using nonconventional means and methods. And I still get goosebumps when I see this big chunk of the industrial landscape in the city, in a building,
sostenido solo por la gravedad sin mortero ni ataduras. Una vez que se construyó y testeó, moverlo a su destino final en el centro de la ciudad para unirlo con el resto del edificio fue pan comido, porque al tener incertidumbres aisladas y haber manejado el riesgo en el ambiente controlado de la cantera, pudimos terminar el edificio a tiempo y dentro del presupuesto, incluso utilizando medios y métodos no convencionales. Aún se me pone la piel de pollo cuando veo este gran macizo del paisaje industrial en la ciudad, en un edificio,
experienced by the visitors and the neighbors. This building gave us quite a few headaches, and so it could have well been an exception in our work, but instead it started to inform a modus operandi where every project becomes this opportunity to test the limits of a discipline we believe has to be urgently reimagined. So what you see here are four homes that we have designed, built and inhabited. Four manifestos where we are using the small scale to ask ourselves big questions. And we are trying to discover the architectures that result from unconventional applications of pretty mundane materials and technologies, like concrete in different forms in the top row, or steel and foam in the bottom row. Take, for instance, these precast concrete beams. You have probably seen them building bridges, highways, water channels -- we found them on one of our visits to a precast concrete factory. And they might not seem especially homey or beautiful, but we decided to use them to build our first house. And this was an incredible moment because we got to be architects as always, builders once more and, for the first time, we could be our own clients. So, here we are trying to figure out how we can take these huge catalogue beams
utilizado por visitantes y vecinos. Esta construcción nos dio algunos dolores de cabeza, y bien podría haber sido una excepción en nuestro trabajo, sin embargo, nos comenzó a informar un modus operandi en el que cada proyecto se convierte en la oportunidad para probar los límites de una disciplina que debería ser reimaginada con urgencia. Lo que ven aquí son cuatro casas que hemos diseñado, construido y habitado. Cuatro manifiestos donde utilizamos una escala menor para hacernos grandes preguntas. Y estamos tratando de descubrir la arquitectura que resulta de la aplicación no convencional de materiales bastante mundanos y tecnologías, como las diferentes formas del concreto usado en la primera hilera, o acero y espuma en la última. Por ejemplo, estas vigas de cemento precolado. Probablemente las han visto en puentes, carreteras, canales hídricos. Nosotros las encontramos en una visita a una fábrica de cemento precolado. Y no se deben haber visto particularmente hogareñas o hermosas, pero decidimos utilizarlas para construir nuestra primera casa. Fue un momento increíble porque debíamos ser arquitectos, una vez más constructores y, por primera vez, podíamos ser nuestros propios clientes. Así que aquí estamos tratando de resolver cómo llevar estas vigas gigantes
of about 20 tons each and stack them progressively around a courtyard space ... the heart of the house. And due to the dimensions and their material quality, these big parts are the structure that carry the loads to the ground, but they are much more than that. They are the swimming pool; they are the walls that divide interior from exterior; they are the windows that frame the views; they are the finishes; they are the very spirit of this house. A house that is for us a laboratory where we are testing how we can use standard elements in nonstandard ways.
de alrededor de 20 toneladas cada una y apilarlas poco a poco en el patio, el corazón de la casa. Debido a las dimensiones y la calidad del material, estas piezas enormes son la estructura que soporta la carga en el terreno. Pero son más que eso. Son la piscina, las paredes que divide el interior del exterior, las ventanas que enmarcan el paisaje, las terminaciones, son el espíritu de la casa. Una casa que es un laboratorio para nosotros donde probamos cómo podemos utilizar elementos comunes de modos no tan comunes.
And we are observing that the results are intriguing.
Y vemos que los resultados son fascinantes.
And we are learning by doing that prefabrication can be much more than stacking boxes or that heavy parts can be airy and transparent. And on top of designing and building this house, we get invaluable feedback, sharing it with our family and our friends because this is our life and our work in progress. The lessons that we learn here get translated into other projects and other programs and other scales as well, and they inspire new work. Here again we are looking at very standard products: galvanized steel studs that can be easily cut and screwed, insulating foams, cement boards -- all materials that you can find hidden in partition walls and that we are exposing; and we are using them to build a very lightweight construction system that can be built almost by anyone. And we are doing it ourselves with our hands in our shop, and we are architects. We're not professional builders but we want to make sure it's possible. And it's so nice that Antón can move it with his hands and Javier can put it in a container, and we can ship it like you would ship your belongings if you were moving abroad ... which is what we did five years ago. We moved our gravity center from Madrid and the house of the concrete beams to Brookline. And we found the ugly duckling of a very nice neighborhood: a one-story garage and the only thing we could afford. But it was OK because we wanted to transform it into a swan, installing on top our just-delivered kit of parts, once more becoming the scientists and the guinea pigs. So this is a house that uses some of the cheapest and most normal materials that you can find in the market that applies the ubiquitous four-by-eight modulation that governs the construction industry. And yet a different organization of the spaces and a different assembly of the parts is able to transform an economically built home into a luxurious space. And now, we're dreaming and we're actively working with developers, with builders, with communities to try to make this a reality for many more homes and many more families. And you see, the world around us is an infinite source of inspiration if we are curious enough to see beneath the surface of things. Now I'm going to take you to the other side of the moon: to the sublime landscape of Montana, where a few years ago we joined Cathy and Peter Halstead to imagine Tippet Rise Art Center on a 10,000-acre working ranch. And when we first visited the site, we realized that all we knew about what an art center is was absolutely pointless for that client, for that community, for that landscape. The kind of white-box museum type had no fit here. So we decided to explode the center into a constellation of fragments, of spaces spread across the vast territory that would immerse the visitors into the wilderness of this amazing place. So back in the office, we are thinking through making, using the land both as support and as material, learning from its geological processes of sedimentation, erosion, fragmentation, crystallization -- explosion -- to discover architectures that are born from the land, that are visceral extensions of the landscape, like this bridge that crosses Murphy Canyon. Or this fountain. Like this space topping a hill ... or this theatre that brings to us the space of the mountains and its sound. And in order to realize this idea, construction cannot be perfectly planned. We need to embrace the drastic weather and the local craft. We need to control just those aspects that are critical, like the structural, the thermal, the acoustical properties embedded in the form. But otherwise, improvisation is welcome and is provoked.
Aprendemos con la práctica que la prefabricación puede ser más que apilar cajas, o que las partes pesadas pueden ser ventiladas y transparentes. Además de diseñar y construir esta casa, al compartir con nuestras familias y amigos, obtenemos respuestas muy valiosas porque es nuestra vida y trabajo en marcha. Las lecciones que aprendemos se convierten en otros proyectos y otros programas como así también en otras habilidades que inspiran nuevos trabajos. Aquí vemos de nuevo productos muy comunes: tachuelas de acero galvanizado que se pueden cortar y atornillar fácilmente, espumas aislantes, placas de cemento. Materiales que puedes encontrar en las paredes de división de una casa y que nosotros mostramos. Materiales que utilizamos para crear un sistema de construcción liviana que pueda utilizar cualquier persona. Lo hacemos con nuestras propias manos, en nuestro negocio. Y somos arquitectos, no constructores profesionales. Pero queremos asegurarnos de que es posible. Es tan lindo que Antón lo pueda mover con sus manos, que Javier lo coloque en un contenedor y que lo podamos transportar como si transportaras tus pertenencias si te mudaras al extranjero, que fue lo que hicimos hace cinco años. Movimos nuestro centro de gravedad y la casa de vigas de concreto de Madrid a Brookline. Y encontramos el patito feo de un barrio muy lindo: un garaje para dos autos y lo único que podíamos pagar. Pero estaba bien porque queríamos transformarlo en un cisne e instalamos nuestros ensamblajes recién llegados. Y nos convertimos una vez más en científicos y conejillos de Indias. Esta es la casa construida con los materiales más baratos y más comunes que puedas encontrar en el mercado que aplica a la modulación omnipresente del cuatro por ocho que regla la industria de la construcción. Aún así, con una organización diferente de los espacios y un ensamblaje diferente de las partes, se puede transformar una casa construida de forma económica en un espacio de lujo. Actualmente, soñamos y trabajamos activamente con desarrolladores, con constructores, con comunidades para hacer de esto una realidad para muchos más hogares y muchas más familias. Como ven, el mundo a nuestro alrededor es una fuente infinita de inspiración si somos lo suficientemente curiosos para ver debajo de la superficie de las cosas. Ahora les mostraré la otra cara de la moneda: el paisaje sublime de Montana, donde hace algunos años junto con Cathy y Peter Halstead imaginamos el Tippet Rise Art Center en un rancho de 4046.8 hectáreas. Cuando visitamos el lugar por primera vez, nos dimos cuenta que todo lo que sabíamos sobre centros de arte no tenía sentido para ese cliente, para esa comunidad, para ese paisaje. El museo con un salón blanco no encajaba aquí. Entonces decidimos estallar el centro en una constelación de fragmentos, de espacios desplegados por el vasto territorio que sumergiría a los visitantes en el desierto de este increíble lugar. En la oficina, pensamos a través de la creación. Utilizamos el suelo como soporte y como material. Aprendemos de sus procesos geológicos de sedimentación, erosión, fragmentación, cristalización, explosión, para descubrir arquitecturas que se originen en el suelo, que sean extensiones viscerales del paisaje, como este puente que cruza Murphy Canyon. O esta fuente. Como este espacio sobre una colina o este teatro que nos lleva al espacio de las montañas y su sonido. Y para entender esta idea la construcción no puede ser planeada a la perfección, necesitamos aceptar el clima drástico y las artesanías del lugar. Necesitamos controlar esos aspectos críticos como la propiedades estructurales, térmicas y acústicas que se encuentran en la forma. Si no, la improvisación es bienvenida e inducida.
And the moment of construction is still a moment of design and a moment of celebration where different hands, hearts, minds come together to perform a final dance. And the result then cannot be anticipated. It comes as a surprise. And we unwrap architecture like you would unwrap a birthday gift. Architecture isn't uncovered: it's discovered. It's extracted from the guts of the earth to build a shelter, one of the most basic human needs. Architecture, art, landscape, archaeology, geology -- all made one. And by using the resources at our disposal in radical ways, by making a space for experimentation, we are able to bring to light architectures that find the beauty latent in the raw and imperfect things that surround us, that elevate them and let them speak their own language. Thank you.
El tiempo de construcción es todavía tiempo de diseño y tiempo de celebración donde diferentes manos, corazones y mentes se juntan para el baile final. El resultado no se puede anticipar. Es una sorpresa. Nosotros desenvolvemos la arquitectura como ustedes abren un regalo. La arquitectura no está descubierta, hay que descubrirla. Se extrae de las entrañas de la tierra para construir un refugio, una de las necesidades más básicas de los seres humanos. Arquitectura, arte, paisaje, arqueología, geología, todos son uno. Y al usar los recursos a nuestro antojo de forma radical, dando lugar a experimentaciones, somos capaces de sacar a la luz arquitecturas que encuentran la belleza latente en cosas imperfectas y en crudo que nos rodean, que las elevan y las dejan hablar su propio idioma. Gracias.
(Applause)
(Aplausos)